# George Mills

# Data Analyst | Full Stack Engineer

919.308.1766 - george.r.mills@gmail.com - github.com/ripplesphere - linkedin.com/in/george-mills-12321a38

#### **ABOUT ME**

I seek furthering my career as a data analyst as this is where my passion lies. My career to date has been as a full stack engineer where I have learned a wide range of technologies in a wide range of environments. Looking at the evolving landscape of computer science what fascinates me the most is Data Analytics. I hope to land a position in a dynamic and challenging role in this budding industry.

## **SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS**

Languages: Python, Java, C++, JavaScript, SQL (MySQL, PostgresSQL, Oracle), Elixir

Specifications: HTML (HTML5, HTML4), CSS (Bootstrap)

Technologies: Power BI, Tableau, Excel (Visualizations, Pivot tables), Git

Environments: Windows, Linux

Methodologies: Agile, Waterfall, OOD

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Nashville Software School | Nashville, Tennessee | Jan - Present

# **Data Analytics Apprentice**

Apprenticeship program utilizing the latest techniques and tools in the data analytics field. Developing visualizations of datasets using PostgreSQL, Power BI, Tableau, and Python libraries.

RippleSphere, Inc | Boston, MA | Dec 2004 – Dec 2020

Online application development and software consulting services

# **Full Stack Developer**

- Designed and developed website including frontend and backend implementation
- Designed and developed Android application utilizing blockchain technology
- Designed and developed web application including ecommerce implementations

John Hancock | Boston, MA | Dec 1999 – Jan 2002

Life insurance, investment, retirement & advice to help individuals reach their goals

# **Software Analyst**

- Prototyped next generation online application submission functionality
- Retrieved and maintained customer records in Oracle datastore

Modify Technologies | Boston, MA | Nov 1998 – Nov 1999

Generate websites from natural language specifications

## **Software Analyst**

 Designed, developed, and test natural language website generation program using backward chaining AI

# **Education**

Nashville Software School | Nashville, TN | Jan – April 2021 Data Analytics Apprentice

**Tufts University** | Medford, MA | Nov 1989 – Oct 1993 Bachelor's of Arts – Computer Science